SFU history collection (Lolita Wilson collector)
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
SFU history collection (Lolita Wilson collector)
1965 - 1993
F-186
Q106661628
6.5 cm of textual records 3 sound recordings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION Collection includes 5 audio cassettes (3 originals, 2 copies). Original sound recordings were digitized in November, 2018.
Wilson, Lolita
Lolita Wilson came to Simon Fraser University in August 1965 as Dean of Women and Associate Professor of Psychology. She subsequently served in a number of positions at the University including Acting Registrar, Dean of Student Affairs, and Assistant to the Vice-President, Academic. She retired from SFU in 1978.
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the contents of the collection and name of the collector.
The collection consists of a draft commentary regarding SFU history, several pieces of corresondence relating to Lolita Wilson's career at SFU, a 1973 oral history interview of Wilson by Liisa Fagerlund (University Archivist at the time), and a copy of the first admissions packet to SFU from the University's opening in 1965. Collection also includes a five-minute cassette, "Sounds of SFU," recorded by arts student Robert Mcaninch in 1970.
The material was arranged by the Archivist.
Wilson, Lolita; Fagerlund, Liisa; Mcaninch, Robert; Sound recordings; Textual records; Records in electronic form (digitized)
The records were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by Lolita Wilson in 1993.
All accessions have been processed as of January 2004. No further accruals are expected.
For other material relating to the career of Lolita Wilson at SFU, see the finding aid to the Campus Community Services Fonds (F-54).
The files are open with no restrictions.
File and item lists are available.
- Lolita Wilson interview, 14 November 1973; F-186-0-0-0-0-1; 2 audio cassettes 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3265, Audio cassette OBJ-3266)
  published
  Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
  Duration: 1 hour, 30 minutes per side
  OBJ-3266 is an exact duplicate of OBJ-3265 and was not digitized.
  Open
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-186-item1, F-186-item2.
  - OBJ-3265_SideA
  - OBJ-3265_SideB
- Lolita Wilson interview, 19 November 1973; F-186-0-0-0-0-2; 2 audio cassettes 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3267, Audio cassette OBJ-3268)
  Duration: 1 hour 7 minutes over two sides.
  OBJ-3268 is an exact duplicate of OBJ-3267 and was not digitized.
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-186-item3, F-186-item4.
  - OBJ-3267_SideA
  - OBJ-3267_SideB
- Sounds of SFU, 1970; F-186-0-0-0-0-3; 1 audio cassette 1 .wav file (Audio cassette OBJ-3269)
  Duration: 5 minutes
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-186-item5.
  - OBJ-3269
- First admissions packet, 1965; F-186-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 186-1)
  Textual records
- Draft SFU history and correspondence, 1971 - 1993; F-186-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 186-1)